Nikhil Yadav

Software Developer

**** 015128364238 **#** 07.09.1995

• Karl-Philipp-Arnd-Strassse 8, 36043, Fulda, Germany

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-yadav-466420188/ https://github.com/nikhilyadavvvv

≅ Summary

Software developer with over 5 years of experience in frontend and backend development. Proficient in Javascript, React, React Native, and other cross-platform and native frameworks for web and mobile development. Strong background in project management and client interaction.

Professional Experience

Software Developer, OB//CC GmbH & Co. KG

06.2019 - present

 Developed several client applications for one of the "supermajors" of Oil and Gas companies as a frontend developer.

Fulda, Germany

- Led the development of several client applications for one of the largest electric utility service providers.
- Developed one-time passwords over SMS generation system assuming the role of full-stack developer.
- Developed a kiosk application for a museum in Fulda as a full-stack developer.
- Researched and implemented critical features utilizing beacon ranging and wearable activity monitoring.
- Assisted in several projects in frontend development.

Web developer (junior), Fidato Infotech Pvt

04.2018 - 12.2018

• Worked as a junior developer on a customer relationship management system

Bhopal, India

- Developed backend for resource management system.
- Did frontend development on internal projects

Web Developer, Ogah Technologies Private Limited

11.2016 - 04.2017

• Developed a browser history tracking system for company employees as a fullstack developer.

Bhopal, India

Skills

- Programming languages: Javascript, Typescript, Dart, Java, C#, PHP, Swift, C, HTML, CSS
- Frameworks: ReactJS, React Native, Flutter, SwiftUI, Unity, Angular, NextJS, Ionic
- Tools: Git, Adobe Photoshop, ProCreate, Blender, ffmpeg
- IDEs: Visual Studio Code, Monocode, PHP Storm, XCode
- Operating Systems: MacOS, Windows

Education

Master of Science, Fulda University of Applied Sciences

04.2019 - present Fulda, Germany

Bachelor of Engineering, Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya

08.2013 - 05.2017

Bhopal, Germany

</> Expertise

ReactJS

Developed several client web apps using the

framework since last 3 years

Flutter

Used framework to develop 2FA android server. Worked with flutter since its initial release.

ExpressJS

Developed microservices to implement critical features in applications

React Native

Developed internal use cross-platform mobile applications since last 2 years

Swift

Developed real-time heart rate measurement companion app for WatchOS

⊗ Languages

English

German

 \bullet \circ \circ \circ

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Nikhil Yadav Fulda, Germany